<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on Enayetur Raheem | এনায়েতুর রহীম</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on Enayetur Raheem | এনায়েতুর রহীম</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating local repository with remote</title>
      <link>/en/2017/07/updating-local-repository-with-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/07/updating-local-repository-with-remote/</guid>
      <description>Working with git for the first time can be time consuming. If you can phrase the right question, you might be luck to find the answer you were looking for. Often, the answers contain some jargons which you are not familiar with.
Here I am listing some common tasts with git</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rmarkdown Examples with R and Python</title>
      <link>/en/2017/07/rmarkdown-with-r-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/07/rmarkdown-with-r-python/</guid>
      <description>This is a chunk of R code
# This is R codex &amp;lt;- rnorm(100)hist(x)y &amp;lt;- rnorm(200)plot(y)# Code in Pythonimport numpy as npx = np.array(10)print(x)## 10Now trying code in SAS
# Code in SAS# Highlights not showingproc sql;select * from aquit;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>আগ্রহী গবেষক খুঁজছি</title>
      <link>/bn/2017/03/looking-for-interested-researcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bn/2017/03/looking-for-interested-researcher/</guid>
      <description>একটা বিড়ালের একটা ইঁদুর খেতে ১ মিনিট লাগলে ১০০টা বিড়ালের ১০০টা ইঁদুর খেতে কয় মিনিট লাগবে? এরকম একটা প্রশ্ন অনেক আগে শুনেছিলাম। সব কন্ডিশন ঠিক থাকলে ১ মিনিটই লাগার কথা। সহজ উত্তর।
আমরা এই মুহূর্তে দুই জন রিসার্চার দুইটি ইন্ডিপেন্ডেন্ট প্রজেক্ট লিড করছি। ৩-৫ মাসের মধ্যে হয়তো ড্রাফট তৈরী হবে। আরো ৬ মাসের মধ্যে আশা করা যায় পাবলিশ হবে অথবা রিভিশন হবে।
অর্থাৎ এই রেইটে বছরে ২টি পাবলিকেশন করা যাবে।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing code embedding in Markdown</title>
      <link>/en/2017/02/code-embedding-in-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/02/code-embedding-in-markdown/</guid>
      <description>This is a chunk of R code
# This is R codex &amp;lt;- rnorm(100)hist(x)y &amp;lt;- rnorm(200)plot(y)Now testing python code# Code in Pythonimport numpy as npx = np.array(10)print(x)## 10Now trying code in SAS# Code in SAS# Highlights not showingproc sql;select * from aquit;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing code embedding in Markdown</title>
      <link>/en/2017/02/code-embedding-in-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/02/code-embedding-in-markdown/</guid>
      <description>This is a chunk of R code
# This is R code x &amp;lt;- rnorm(100) hist(x)  # Code in Python import numpy as np x = np.array(10) print(x)  ## 10  Now trying code in SAS
# Code in SAS # Highlights not showing proc sql; select * from a quit;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sample Page</title>
      <link>/cool/sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cool/sample/</guid>
      <description>This is a sample page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Found</title>
      <link>/404/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/404/</guid>
      <description>Page not found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ডেটা সায়েন্স কী এবং ডেটা সায়েন্টিস্ট কারা?</title>
      <link>/bn/2016/11/data-science-and-data-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bn/2016/11/data-science-and-data-scientist/</guid>
      <description>ডেটা সায়েন্স এখন হট টপিক।
একাডেমিয়া থেকে ইন্ডাস্ট্রিতে চলে আসার পর প্রথম যে সমস্যা অনুভব করেছি সেটা হলো কাউকে সহজে বোঝানো যায় না আমি কী করি। আমেরিকাতে ইউনিভার্সিটির শিক্ষকদের প্রফেসর বলে। প্রফেসর বললে সবাই বোঝে কাজটা কী। ইন্ডাস্ট্রিতে কাজ করছি ডেটা সায়েন্টিস্ট হিসেবে। কেউ জিজ্ঞেস করলে এক কথায় যদি বলি ডেটা সায়েন্টিস্ট, তখন অবধারিতভাবে মুখের অভিব্যক্তি পরিবর্তিত হয়ে ভাবটা এমন হয় যেন ডেটা সায়েন্টিস্ট&amp;ndash; সেটা আবার কী?
অনেকে প্রশ্ন করে -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>বাংলাদেশে পরিসংখ্যানবিদদের ভবিষ্যৎ</title>
      <link>/bn/2016/10/future-of-statistics-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bn/2016/10/future-of-statistics-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <description>একটা বিষয় আমাকে আশাবাদী করে যখন দেখি আমাদের ছাত্র-ছাত্রীরা পরিসংখ্যানে পড়াশুনা করছে এবং তাদের মধ্যে অল্প কয়েকজন বাদে সবাই ডিগ্রী শেষ করছে। স্নাতক পর্যায়ে আমাদের প্রতিটি পাবলিক বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়েই পরিসংখ্যান পড়ানো হয়। সে হিসেবে প্রতি বছর আনুমানিক ২-৪শ&amp;rsquo;র মতো ছাত্রছাত্রী পরিসংখ্যানে স্নাতক অর্জন করে। সংখ্যাটি একেবারে কম নয়।
আমি দিনের একটা উল্লেখযোগ্য সময় ফেইসবুকে সময় দেই। এর অন্যতম উদ্যেশ্য আমাদের নতুন-পুরাতন ছাত্র-ছাত্রীদের সাথে যুক্ত থাকা। একটা সময় ছিল যখন শুধু পরিসংখ্যানের কেউ হলেই তাকে আমি ফ্রেন্ড হিসেবে যুক্ত করতাম। এখনো করি তবে এখন পরিসংখ্যানের বাইরেও বন্ধু-সার্কেল বেড়েছে।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing R Markdown</title>
      <link>/en/2015/07/testing-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2015/07/testing-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
\(\bar{X} = \frac{\sum x_i}{n}\)
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/about/</guid>
      <description>I am statistician by training with more than 15 years of experience in academia and industry combined. As a data scientist in clinical neurosciences, I work with clinicians and program directors and utilize machine learning algorithms to uncover information hidden in the massive amount of unprocessed healthcare data.
I have over 10 years of experience in building predictive models utilizing statistical techniques to evaluate scenarios and to make predictions on future outcomes in order to solve complex business problems that support decision making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>/en/vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/vitae/</guid>
      <description>Enayetur Raheem, PhD Data Scientist (Neurosciences)
Carolinas HealthCare System 720 E Morehead St.
Charlotte, NC 28202, USA
Employments    Years Institution     Jun 2016 ~ Data Scientist, Carolinas HealthCare System, Charlotte, NC, USA   Aug 2013 ~ May 2016 Assistant Professor of Applied Statistics, University of Northern Colorado, Greeley, CO, USA   Aug 2012 ~ May 2013 Assistant Professor of Statistics, University of Wisconsin-Green Bay, Green Bay, WI, USA   Jan 2010 ~ Aug 2012 Data Analyst, Windsor-Essex County Health Unit, Windsor, Ontario, Canada    Education  PhD in Statistics, 2012, University of Windsor, Windsor, Ontario, Canada Masters in Statistics, 2005, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada Masters in Applied Statistics, 2000, University of Dhaka, Bangladesh  Current Projects Chickungunya The following is from Wikipedia 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>2017  Hossain, M. S., Raheem, E., Sultana, T. A., Ferdous, S., Nahar, N., Islam, S., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Khatun, H. (2017). Thalassemias in South Asia: clinical lessons learnt from Bangladesh. Orphanet Journal of Rare Diseases, 12(1), 93.  2016  Dey, S., &amp;amp; Raheem, E. (2016). Multilevel multinomial logistic regression model for identifying factors associated with anemia in children 6–59 months in northeastern states of India. Cogent Mathematics, 3(1), 1159798.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>My research is focused on building better predictive models through improved estimation of regression parameters. I am interested in the development and application of James-Stein type shrinkage estimation in parametric and semiparametric regression models and their comparisons with penalty estimators. In the event of a trade-off between bias and prediction error, James-Stein-type methods tend to achieve reduced overall prediction error that offsets the bias in the estimation.
Thalassemias Thalassemias are emerging as a global public health concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>আমি</title>
      <link>/bn/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bn/about/</guid>
      <description>আমি এনায়েত।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>সিভি</title>
      <link>/bn/vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bn/vitae/</guid>
      <description>নাম শিক্ষা আমার সিভি</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>